ニーニウ
Nieniu!
よかった　ニーニウ
Oh, I'm so relieved...
Nieniu...
本影音版权属其出版、发行方，字幕制作仅供学术交流之用 请于下载后24小时内删除，并不得有公开传播或作商业盈利之行为 若有违法等相关行为，诸神字幕组恕不承担任何法律或连带责任。
翻译 koki  放 晴  La Fatalité
Hi!
はーい　先程はどうも
Thanks for before.
压制 暗之亚瑟王  校对 凉YAN Lucifer 时间 Lucifer
ハミュッツ＝メセタ
Hamyuts Meseta.
しつこい女
You're a tenacious woman.
あっちでは殺されちゃったけどさ
I was killed back there,
but I'll tell you a secret.
教えてあげる
あんたにあたしは殺せないの
You can't finish me.
うん？
Chacoly offered you her love
and tried to kill you.
チャコリーはあんたに愛を捧げて殺そうとした
あたしはあんたに何を捧げると思う
Care to guess what I'm gonna offer you?
さあ　興味がない
Not particularly, no.
Fool.
愚か
なかなかよかったわよ
That was pretty good.
でも　まだ足りないの
Alas, it wasn't enough...
ねえ　もっとすごいの　頂戴よ
Say, think you can give me
something better?!
Why won't you die?
なぜ死なない
Oh, that's the good stuff, Ruruta...
最高よ　ルルタ
爪先までびりびり来るわ
You're making my toes curl.
So, you think you could
なんたってあんたは　何度だって殺してくれる
kill me over and over again?!
I see. Makia's a powerful man, indeed.
なるほど　大した男だ　マキア
You're way off. It's against the rules
for the man to lose interest first.
いやだ　男の方から覚めるなんてルール違反よ
Makia gave you the ability
to take pleasure in death.
お前がマキアから与えられた能力は
「死の快楽」
These nonentity entrails are solely
a world for bodiless souls.
この仮想臓腑は　肉体のない魂だけの世界
Only by losing your heart
can your soul receive death.
心の敗北だけが　魂に死を与えることができる
Put another way, even if you're obliterated
in battle, unless your heart is defeated,
逆にいえば　攻撃を喰らっても
心が敗北しなければ　魂は死なない
your soul cannot die.
An example would be if one enjoys death.
例えば　死　そのものが快楽ならば
I'm impressed how quickly you deduced that.
やるわね　こんなにあっさり気が付くなんて
You're right. Makia reprogrammed me.
そうよ　マキアはあたしを作り変えた
苦痛を歓喜　死を快楽に変えるように
To take joy from pain...
To take pleasure from death...
You're not human.
人間じゃない
That's right. We're not human.
そう　人間じゃない
We're nothing more than mere tools.
あたしたちはただの道具
Hey, wanna bring a tool into the bedroom?
ねえ　道具を使ったプレイって　どう
This...
これは…
What am I feeling?
なんだ　この感覚は
まるで　ニーニウとのあの一夜
It's just like that night I spent with Nieniu...
さあ　いいのよ
Go ahead... It's okay.
本能のままに貪りなさい
Feast on your true desire...
Stone pellets of sweet death.
甘き死の轢弾を
诸
神字幕组
剥がれ落ちた夢 澱む幻
Hagare ochita yume yodomu maboroshi
もう この世界を見放した者さえ
Mou kono sekai wo mihanashita
mono sae tsutsumi komu kotoba
包み込む言葉
刹那に消えゆく
Setsuna ni kieyuku
共に囚われの明日を取り戻そう
Tomo ni toraware no ashita wo torimodosou
何もかも失くしても
Nani mo kamo nakushite mo
最期の審議の日まで　ずっと
Saigo no shingi no hi made
Zutto hana no you ni tsuyoku sakihokore
花のように強く咲き誇れ
絶望のオト　拾い集めて
Zetsubou no oto hiroi atsumete
永久に奏でる　ストレインに変える
Towa ni kanaderu sutorein ni kaeru
Wazukana hikari sugaritsuitemo todomaru kara
僅かなヒカリ　すがりついても
留まるから
届けたい　残らず
Todoketai nokorazu
第26话 赎罪
与
Episode 26
Atonement, Delusion, and Books Within Books
疑惑
和
书中的书
I, Lascall Othello, exist for no purpose
but to continue the tale,
このラスコール＝オセロは
ただ物語に続きを与え　それを眺めるだけの存在
watching as it unfolds.
However, this obvious plot
approaching the ending
しかし　こうまで結末の分かり切った展開
has left this captive spectator feeling bored.
観客たる私にとっては　いささか興ざめでございます
Wh-What is this...
なんだ　これ…は
Take this!
Get hit by these rocks and
you'll feel just like I do.
この轢弾を受けるとあたしと同じ気分になろう
Doesn't it feel good?
どう　快感でしょう
Enough to make you want to die!
それこそ死にたくなるような
No! I must not die!
駄目だ　今死ぬわけにはいかん
I have to save Nieniu...
僕はニーニウを…
I have to save Nieniu!
Hey, Ruruta.
ねえ　ルルタ　死にたいのはあたしたちだけじゃ…ないみたいよ
Looks like we're not the only
ones who want to die.
Please kill me...
俺を　殺してくれ
Kill me!
殺してくれ
俺はルルタに騙された
I was tricked by you!
俺の魔法権利がルルタの力になるなんて真っ平御免だ
I'm sick of my magic right
belonging to your power!
Put me out of my misery!
もう　殺してくれ
Y-You men...
お前たち…
All right! Go ahead and die!
さあ　死になさい
I'll make each and every one of you feel great!
誰も彼も　皆気持ちよくしてあげる
lmpossible. My power... Leaving me?
嘘だ　力が撒けていく
I can die! I can die!
死てるぞ　最高の気分だ
This is pure ecstasy!
そうか　僕の力は彼らの「本」
That's right! My power comes from their books.
Do not die!
死ぬな　お前たち　死ぬんじゃない
You men cannot die!
At long last!
やったぞ
待って
Wait!
理解したかしら　ルルタ
Have you figured it out yet, Ruruta?
あんたは弱い　あんたは無能
You're weak.
You're incompetent.
無能で無才　無力で無様
Incompetent and talentless.
Powerless and pathetic!
負けるわけにはいかない
I cannot die.
Countless men and women
have been sacrificed,
幾多な犠牲を積み重ねたのは　全てニーニウを幸せにするため
all for the sake of Nieniu's happiness!
What a cheap ending.
なんと言え　あっけない結末でしょう
At this rate...
このままでは
ハミュッツ様は　負ける
Lady Hamyuts will falter.
Ruruta will not give up.
ルルタは挫けない
ルルタは怯まない
Ruruta will not run away.
ルルタは恐れず
Ruruta feels no fear.
ルルタは決して負けない
Ruruta will not be defeated.
Hey now. What are you babbling about...
ちょっと　何ぶつぶつ言っ…
Why?
なぜなら　ルルタのすべては　ニーニウのためにあるからだ
Because my entire being exists to please Nieniu!
Kill Ruruta!
ルルタを殺せ
Magic Right Transference.
魔法権利譲渡　対象はニーニウ
End target is Nieniu.
Transfer the entirety of my power.
僕の持つすべての力を
譲渡　完了
Transfer completed.
Hamyuts, your life must have been rough,
ハミュッツさん　さぞ辛かったことでしょう
ルルタを殺すために道具を
existing simply as a tool designed to kill Ruruta.
そのためだけに生かされるなんて
I am to blame. I apologize.
私のせいです　御免なさい
許されることではありません
It is not something that can be forgiven.
ですがせめて　私に出来ることを為しために
However, I will fulfill the one
deed I am able to do.
ほんの少しでも　罪を償うために
To atone for sins, if only a tiny portion...
これから　これから　殺して差し上げます
I shall now...
I shall now grant you the gift of death.
「因果抹消」　膨大
Causality-Nullification Effect... Spread.
I am the soul of destruction.
私は滅びの魂　すべての死を求める私に
I yearn for the death of all things.
Your sling shot has no effect on me.
あなたの轢弾は響かない
もう無理をしないんでいいんです
You needn't struggle uselessly anymore.
You are no longer a tool.
あなたはもう　道具ではない
What?!
なにを
そう　あなたはもう　死に快楽を求める魂ではないのです
Yes, you are no longer a soul
that seeks pleasure in death.
Please listen closely to the voice of your heart.
どうか　自分の心の声に耳を傾けて
You spent countless peaceful
afternoons with your companions...
仲間達と　にぎやかな昼下がりを過ごし
Felt the pure, beautiful love of so many.
多くの　美しく清らかな愛に触れ
そして　マット＝アラストを　愛した
And...
You loved Mattalast.
Death, in the world of those
you wish to protect,
守りたいものが生まれた世界は
死は　激しい痛みと変わるのです
becomes nothing but wretched pain.
Come now. End the pain.
早く　楽になりましょう
I shall grant you a death replete with love.
愛ある死を　与えてあげますから
Damn it...
くそ　くそ
Damn it!
これでいいはずだ
This is as it should be.
ニーニウは勝利し
Nieniu wins,
彼女の望む世界の滅びがやってくる
and the world of destruction
she desires comes to pass.
なのに　なぜなんだ？
And yet, something feels off.
違和感を感じる
Like I'm losing something immensely important...
何か大事なことが　失われているような
Damn you... Damn you!
この…　この…
I'll kill every last one of you!
お前たち　殺す
絶望ごとまるごと　殺してやる
I'll kill off all the despair
you bring to the world!
Run all you want, nothing will change.
どこへ逃げても同じです
Hamyuts, you have nowhere to escape.
ハミュッツさん
あなたに逃げ場所はないのです
Death is the only place where
your soul can rest in peace.
あなたの魂が　安らげる場所は死しかないのです
Will this be your final resting
place, Hamyuts Meseta,
ここで死ぬのか　ハミュッツ＝メセタ
buried in the pathetic, greedy, gaudy red earth?
えげつない　はしたないな毒々しい赤い血
雌豚にぴったりの汚らしい死に化粧だ
What a perfectly filthy death
mask for a sow like you.
Is that...
あれが　コリオ＝トニス
Colio Tonies?
コリオ＝トニス
久しぶりね　会いたかったのよ
Long time no see.
I missed you.
待ってよ　どこに行くの
Hold on. Where are you going?
こんなとこで女を一人にするつもり？
You'd leave a woman all alone out here?
ハミュッツ＝メセタは一人じゃない
Hamyuts Meseta is not alone.
あんたまでそんなことを
You're spouting that crap, too?
あたしはね　死を愛してる　孤独を愛してる
I love death, all right?!
I love solitude!
だからこそ　たった一人の妹まで殺せたのよ
That's how I was able to kill
my one and only sister!
ねえ そうでしょう
Don't you see?!
あたしはルルタを倒す　ただそれだけ
I will kill Ruruta! That's all...
That's all I've lived my life to do.
ただ　それだけのために生きてきたのに
So why...
それじゃあ　あたしは
Why was I born?!
あたしは何で生まれてきたのよ
In order to...
仲間と
...meet your comrades and those you love.
愛すべき人たちと出会うために
Shiron Byacornise.
シロン＝ブーヤコーニッシュ
僕は　一人じゃない
I am not alone.
ハミュッツ＝メセタも
And Hamyuts Meseta,
neither are you.
一人じゃない
I'm...
あたしは　一人じゃ…ない
not alone?
Damn it!
ニーニウ　君は幸せか
Nieniu, are you happy?
Happy? What nonsense.
幸せ？　戯れ言ですね
懸命に生きる彼らが手に掛ける語らない
I am forced to kill those who've
clung so hard to life.
彼らの痛みは　私の痛みです
Their pain is my pain.
でも　それは君のため…
But that's so you can...
私がそれを望みましたか？
Did I ever wish for it?
What?
え？
Due to your selfish actions,
あなたの勝手な思い込みのせいで
世界は傷付き　涙したのです
the world sheds tears from
the pain inflicted upon it.
早く滅ぼしてあげればよかったのに
Destroying it at the start
would have been better.
痛みもなかったか
It would have been painless for them,
not even realizing they'd died.
死んだことすら気付かないのかしら
Nieniu?
ニーニウ
この世界が滅んでも　あなたの罪は許されません
Even if the world is destroyed,
your sins will remain unforgiven.
Ruruta Coozancoona,
ルルタ＝クーザンクーナ
私は　あなたを許しません
I will never forgive you!
Ruruta is crying?
ルルタが　泣いている？
まだ物語には　先があるのですね
Looks like this tale isn't over yet.
見てみたい　その先を
I want to know what happens next.
そのためには　誰かを目覚めさせる必要がある
To do that, I need to wake someone up.
例え　高すぎる観覧料を取られるとしても
Even if the price of admission is too high...
ミレポっく様
Lady Milepoc.
ああ　やはり
Yes, I knew it. This lowly stone
sword was being too nosy.
ただの石剣には　ですぎた真似でした
So now I... Now I get...
これこそ　これこそが　読めぬ物語
An unreadable tale...
ありえぬ結末の　最たるもの
An unfathomable ending. A supreme being.
あなたは　ちょっと
You... Hey, are you asleep?
眠ってるの
Wake...
死んでる
She's dead?
誰か　返事をして
Does anyone copy?
そんな　どうして誰も
That's odd... Why doesn't anyone respond?
そんな
This can't be...
Right!
そうだ　代行
Acting Director!
眠っているの　起きて
Are you asleep? Wake up!
Please wake up!
起きて頂戴
Why?
どうして
Acting Director!
代行
N-No...
いや　いやだ　いやだ
No!
助けて　代行
Help me, Acting Director...
ヴォルケン＝マクマーニ
Volken Macmani...
I had forgotten about you.
今まで忘れていた
My... My...
私の…　私の…
ヴォルケンを　代行が殺した
My Volken was killed by the Acting Director?
Live on, Milepoc.
生き延びなさい　ミレポ
Without your power, it's all for naught.
あんたの力がなけりゃ意味がないの
Your job is to stay alive, no matter what.
あんたの仕事は　何がなんでも死なないこと
死んだら　承知しないわよ
I'd better not hear you've died.
I don't understand any of this.
分からないことばかり
ルルタのことだけじゃない
Not just about Ruruta, but the
Acting Director and Volken, too...
代行のことも　ヴォルケンのことも
But...
でも　みんながそれぞれの想いを胸に戦って来たことだけは分かる
I do know that they all fought with
their hearts, for their own reasons.
私は今一人かもしれない
I may be all alone now,
but...
でも…
ニーニウは　僕をもう求めてはいない
Nieniu no longer cares for me.
Whether the world is destroyed or not,
世界が滅びても　滅びずとも
ニーニウが喜ぶことはない
Nieniu will never feel happiness.
This fight has lost all meaning.
この戦いに　意味はない
Life itself has lost all meaning.
生きることに　意味も
やっと見付けた
I finally found you.
お前は　確か　コリオ＝トニス
Wait, you're... Colio Tonies.
I see you also address me by name.
君も　僕を名前で呼んでくれるんだね
That's right, Colio. He calls you by name.
そうよ　コリオ　彼はあなたを名前で呼ぶの
僕はシロン＝ブーヤコーニッシュの「本」を食べていないはずだ
I never ate Shiron Byacornise's book.
なのになぜ　なぜ君とともにいる
So why? Why is she here with you?
I used to have nothing at all.
僕は何も持っていなかった
でも今は持っている
But now I have the person I love
愛する人と　そしてこのナイフを
and this knife.
Huh?
このナイフをあなたに
We give this knife to you.
To me?
僕に？
君が守ったこの世界で　僕はシロンに会えた
It was within the world you
protected that I met Shiron.
生きることには意味がある
Life has meaning.
愛することには意味があると
It's thanks to you that I learned
that love carries meaning.
君のおかげで知ることができた
You haven't lost it yet.
まだ　あなたは失っていない
心が動いている限り
Not as long as your heart beats...
ありがとう　ルルタ＝クーザンクーナ
Thank you, Ruruta Coozancoona.
Thank you.
ありがとう
I obtained countless tales,
僕は　多くの物語を手に入れた
そのどれもが　ニーニウを幸せにできるものではなかった
and there wasn't a person capable of giving
Nieniu happiness in a single one.
But in of each and every one of them,
だが　その一つ一つには確実に幸せが存在した
happiness clearly existed.
そうだ　僕は最初から知っていたじゃないか
That's it! I knew the answer all along.
All the people who stood up
for something, with nothing,
何も持たずに　何かに立ち向かい
そして　尊いものを得てきた者たちを
and yet managed to find something precious...
僕はこの体に　宿し続けてきたじゃないか
They've existed inside my body all along.
The dream that's fallen away and the stagnant illusion
I can see it now.
今なら　見える
The dream that's fallen away and the stagnant illusion
The words embrace even the ones
who have abandoned this world
Ruruta, atone for your sins.
The words embrace even the ones
who have abandoned this world
ルルタ　罪を償うんです
The words embrace even the ones
who have abandoned this world
Ruruta.
The words embrace even the ones
who have abandoned this world
ルルタ
The words embrace even the ones
who have abandoned this world
Disappearing instantly
Let's take back the imprisoned tomorrow together
Hamyuts?
ハミュッツさん
Let's take back the imprisoned tomorrow together
いやだけど　仕方ないのよね
I didn't want to do it, but what are you gonna do?
Let's take back the imprisoned tomorrow together
Even if we lose everything
They like following my orders,
for whatever reason.
Even if we lose everything
あいつら　なんだかんだ言ってあたしの命令を聞くのが好きだしさ
They like following my orders,
for whatever reason.
Until the judgment day
They like following my orders,
for whatever reason.
Keep on blooming proudly like flowers
You...
あなたは…
Watch me as I use it, 'kay?
Keep on blooming proudly like flowers
使わせてもらうわよ
Watch me as I use it, 'kay?
Pick up the sounds of despair
The abominable power that rests within me...
この身に宿したおぞましい力
Pick up the sounds of despair
Hamyuts Meseta's true power.
ハミュッツ＝メセタの本当の能力
Play it forever and change it into strain
Now come forth!
さあ　来なさい
I'll stick around, clinging onto the subtle light
あたしの愛する大馬鹿ども
All you idiots who love me!
I'll stick around, clinging onto the subtle light
I want to convey it until there's nothing left
Huh? What is this place?
あれ　ここ　どこでしょう
You...
これは…
Tobu hane yume toraete
Tobu mane yami oyoideru
Aoku kanashii sora ni kotae kiite miyou
Shimaru tobira tataita (tsuyoku)
Nukedashite saigo no aisatsu
Dare wo sagashi tsuzuketa no to
Koe wo ubawareru dake de wakaranai
Oreta ai no seide
Nanimokamo nakushita ima
Tenshi wa mou konai
Dominant Space
命を戦え
Fight for life.
Pray for life.
命を祈れ
Sing for life.
命を歌え
Upon the raised fists...
振り上げた拳に
Upon those who clench them...
しかと握り締めたの
Shine upon them, life!
命を輝け
世界之力
The Power of the World
Shine upon them, life!